AKHIL Puthanpurayil Kutti Punathil

Email: pkakhil95@gmail.com | Phone: 8921519441

Summary

Data Scientist with comprehensive expertise in data processing, predictive modelling and data labelling algorithms. Solid theoretical exposure to machine learning, deep learning, and NLP. Proven experience in conversational design, manual testing, and chatbot evaluation. Possesses an Engineering degree with confidence in programming.

Employment History

Prompt Engineer (Remotasks- Freelance Feb 2023- Jan 2024)

- Contributed significantly to the advancement of generative AI models through diverse writing projects in Malayalam.
- Evaluated and ranked responses generated by Al models.
- Crafted engaging short stories on specific topics.
- Assessed the factual accuracy of Al-generated text.
- Developed a deep understanding of the nuances of the Malayalam language.
- Played a key role in refining and training Al models for improved language-related tasks.

Quality Assurance Analyst (Saarathi.ai June 2022-Jan 2023)

- Conducted regression testing on chatbots before release.
- Analysed calls and updated issues related to NLU, NER, ASR, etc.
- Updated production data model daily for 0 error accuracy.
- Performed data tagging for NER and NLU.
- Checked user experience and prepared response templates.
- Worked on audio verification and ASR testing.

Data Associate (Saarathi.ai Dec 2021-May 2022)

- Specialised in conversational design chatbot testing manually and using tools like Postman.
- Tested voice bots for Manappuram, Kredit Bee, and Bajaj Finserv.
- Analysed call quality of automated voice bots, conducted ASR testing, and fixed bugs.
- Contributed to various project requirements for training the model.

Machine Learning Intern (Mavenai Technologies Sep 2021-Mar 2022)

Annotated vehicle parts for an insurance company using label-me.

- Created datasets for machine learning models.
- Studied basic machine learning and OpenCV.

Data Scientist Internship (Zummit Info Labs Llp, virtual Jun 2021 - Sep 2021)

- Worked on protein structure prediction using dimensionality reduction methods.
- Conducted data cleaning and delved into deep learning.

Education

- Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical Engineering-2018)
 New Horizon College of Engineering (Bangalore, Karnataka)
- NSDC_NASSCOM Certification in AI & Machine Learning Engineering (Level 7) -- (2021)
 - Aura Educational Society (Trivandrum, Kerala)

Technical Skills

- Python
- Machine Learning
- Excel
- Conversational Al
- Chatbot
- Postman
- Prompt Engineering

Areas of Interest

- Data Science
- Data Analytics
- Conversational Al

Data Science Concepts

- Probability and Statistics
- Machine Learning (Supervised and Unsupervised)
- Regression and Classification Algorithms
- Dimensionality Reduction
- Clustering Algorithms
- Neural Networks
- Sentiment Analysis

Projects

- Response Modelling of Bank Marketing Campaign
- Personal Al Assistant
- Predict the Sentiments of Amazon Customer

Github: https://github.com/akhilai-ban

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the above-mentioned details are true to the best of my knowledge.